Finding Aid for International Order of The King’s Daughters and Sons. Phoebe Beal Circle (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1911-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
International Order of The King’s Daughters and Sons. Phoebe Beal Circle (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1911-1994
International Order of The King’s Daughters and Sons. Phoebe Beal Circle (Ann Arbor, Mich.).
2.0 linear feet
851513 Bk.w 2
Minutes, group records, and other records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the organization (Donor No. 3820 ) in multiple accessions.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Founded in 1886, The King's Daughters was established as an international, interdenominational organization, the purpose of which was "the development of spiritual life and the stimulation of Christian activities through religious, educational, philanthropic, and charitable programs." Being a member involved both sharing the purposes and goals of the organization, as well as being a Christian. In 1891, the organization was renamed The International Order of the King's Daughters and Sons.
In 1911 the Phoebe Beal Circle, named after an active member of the First Methodist Church who was married to Ann Arbor businessman, Rice Beal, was established in Ann Arbor, Michigan, by ten or eleven women. It would later grow into an organization consisting of eleven groups, each of which "being an integral part of the whole." Included among the achievements of the Phoebe Beal Circle was the work they did for children confined to the University Hospital for long periods of time. Concern for the education and entertainment of these children resulted in volunteers being sent to read to them, and out of this project grew a Sunday school class known as "In His Name." Starting in 1922, a part-time teacher, and later four full-time teachers were hired to educate those children who had fallen behind in their school work due to their stay at the hospital. This work eventually was recognized by the Michigan Branch of The King's Daughters, and eventually all the state circles of the organization joined to help with the school. Finally the Regents of the University of Michigan, realizing the importance of the school, later included it in their budget, naming it the Hospital School of the University of Michigan. The Phoebe Beal Circle continues its work into the 1990s.
The records of the Phoebe Beal Circle of the International Order of the King's Daughters and Sons measures 2.0 linear feet. The records, dating from 1911 to 1994, have been arranged into four series - Printed Material, Minutes, Group Records, and Other Records.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; International Order of the King's Daughters and Sons. Phoebe Beal Circle (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
- Printed material
  - Brief history, 1969; bylaws, and related (Box 1)
- Minutes
  - 1911-1966 and 1974-1983, 14 volumes (Box 1)
- Group records
  - Group 7 (?) minute book, 1938-1941 (Box 2)
  - Group 8
    - Agenda, 1968-1979 (Box 2)
    - Minute books, 1940-1988, 1 volume and 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Group 9
    - Agenda, 1981-1986 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
  - Group Unknown
    - Minutes, 1953-1962, 2 notebooks (Box 2)
- Other records
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Deichert (Mrs. Norwood), secretary book relating to the Michigan Branch's involvement with Michigan's Native Americans (Box 2)
  - Junior King's Daughters minutes, 1937-1940 (Box 2)
  - Membership lists (Box 2)
  - Michigan Branch's board meeting and convention records, 1979-1994 (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
  - President's yearly reports, 1959-1977 (Box 2)